Guide to the Oral History of the American Left Collection OH.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Oral History of the American Left Main Series, 1940-2011
  - Michael Harrington, May 2, 1988; cuid1319 (Box 4, Cassette 117.5 A-C, Box 17, Cd Harrington 3-5)
    Duration: 190 minutes in three parts
  - Daniel Heartquist, Feb 5, 1981; cuid1320 (Box 7, Folder 46, Box 4, Cassette 118 A-B, Box 18, Cd Heartquist 1-2)
    Interview covers the Socialist movement in Sweden, Swedish-American Socialism, the Left in New England during the 1930s-1940s, and reflections on American Communism.
  - James B. Henry, May 11, 1976; cuid1321 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    Interview documents the legal prosecution of the International Workers Order in New York State during the 1950s and Henry's role as ex-Special Assistant Attorney General.
    Interview by Howard Brown.
  - Michael Henry, Jun 4, 1980; cuid1322 (Box 4, Cassette 119 A-B, Box 18, Cd M. Henry 1-2)
    Duration: 82 minutes in two parts
  - Philip Hochstein, Oct 28, 1986; cuid1323 (Box 10, Cassette 424, Box 18, Cd Hochstein 1)
    Interview includes discussion of immigration from Russian Empire, youth in Bayonne, New Jersey, and the press and the Left.
    Interview by Diana Maull.
  - Otis Hood, Mar 24, 1981; cuid1324 (Box 4, Cassette 120 A-B, Box 18, Cd Hood 1-2)
    Interview includes discussion of Hood's union-family background, the New England Left in the 1930s, the Communist Party in Vermont during the 1930s, the Communist Party in Boston during the 1930s-1940s, Hood's experience in prison, and other reflections.
  - Walter Hoops, Oct 6, 1984; cuid1325 (Box 4, Cassette 121 A-B, Box 7, Folder 48, Box 18, Cd Hoops 1-2)
    Interview documents the Saint Louis Free Thought movement from the nineteenth century to 1940s, Hoops' background in Germany, his immigration to the United States, the Rand School of Social Science, the Socialist Party in Saint Louis during the 1930s, and Free Thought and atheism in Saint Louis from the 1940s-1980s.
    Duration: 73 minutes in two parts
  - Frank Horzen, Oct 26, 1982; cuid1326 (Box 4, Cassette 122, Box 7, Folder 49, Box 18, Cd Horzen 1)
    Interview consists of an analysis of politics in Fontana, California by member of the religious (anti-socialist) South Slav benefit association and steel worker, who later became mayor of Fontana. Also covers are attitudes toward Henry Kaiser and later (Third World) immigrants.
  - International Labor Defense, Jun 21, 1982; cuid1327 (Box 18, Cd ILD 1-3, Box 4, Cassette 124 A-C)
    Interview with David Freedman, Sam Neuberger, and Fay Pasternak on International Labor Defense, National Lawyers Guild, and radical legal work in the 1930s-1940s. Interview includes recollections of Joe Brodsky, Carol King, Vito Marcantonio, and others.
    Interview by Ann Ginger and Debra Bernhardt.
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, Anonymous Woman 1, Oct 22, 1974; cuid1328 (Box 4, Cassette 123 A, Box 18, Cd ILGWU 6)
    Interview by David Gurowsky.
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, Anonymous Man 1, Oct 22, 1974; cuid1329 (Box 4, Cassette 123 B, Box 18, Cd ILGWU 1, Box 2, Cassette 123 A, Cd ILGWU 6)
    Interview is on track 1 of CD ILGWU 1.
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, Anonymous Woman 2, Feb 10, 1975; cuid1330 (Box 4, Cassette 123 C, Box 18, Cd ILGWU 7)
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, Anonymous Man 2, Dec 16, 1974; cuid1331 (Box 4, Cassette 123 D, Box 18, Cd ILGWU 8, Cd ILGWU 2, Box 2, Cassette 123 E)
    Interview is on track 2 of CD ILGWU 2.
    The narrator discusses work in the garment industry and figures in the ILGWU during the 1910s-1940s.
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, Anonymous Man 3, Oct 24, 1974 (Box 18, Cd ILGWU 3, Box 4, Cassette 123 G, Box 1, Cd ILGWU 9, Box 2, Cassette 123 F)
    Interview is on track 2 of CD ILGWU 3.
    - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, Anonymous Woman 3, Oct 23, 1974; cuid1332 (Box 4, Cassette 123 F, Box 18, Cd ILGWU 3)
      Interview is on track 1 of CD ILGWU 3.
      Duration: 60 minutes
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, Anonymous Woman 4, Nov 19, 1974; cuid1333 (Box 4, Cassette 123 E, Box 18, Cd ILGWU 2)
    Interview is on track 1 of CD ILGWU 2.
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, Anonymous Woman 5, Dec 27, 1974; cuid1334 (Box 4, Cassette 123 H, Box 18, Cd ILGWU 4)
    Interview is on track 1 of CD ILGWU 4.
    Duration: 23 minutes
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, Anonymous Woman 6, Oct 22, 1974; cuid1335 (Box 18, Cd ILGWU 1, Box 4, Cassette 123 B)
    Interview is on track 2 of CD ILGWU 1.
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, Anonymous Woman 7, Mar 12, 1975; cuid1336 (Box 18, Cd ILGWU 10, Box 4, Cassette 123 J, Box 3, Cassette 123 I, Cd ILGWU 5)
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, Anonymous Woman 8, Jan 2, 1975; cuid1337 (Box 18, Cd ILGWU 8, Box 4, Cassette 123 D, Cd ILGWU 4, Box 2, Cassette 123 H)
    Interview is on track 2 of CD ILGWU 4.
  - Evelyn Irsay, Jun 1982; cuid1338 (Box 18, Cd Irsay 1, Box 10, Cassette 383)
  - CLR James, Feb 25, 1974; cuid1339 (Box 81, Cassette 369, Box 18, Cd James 1-2)
    Recording of a speech titled "Africa and World Politics" at the University of Rhode Island.
    Recorded by Paul Buhle.
  - CLR James, Oct 15, 1981; cuid1340 (Box 81, Cassette 369, Box 18, Cd James 3)
  - Abdeen Jabara, Mar 28, 1983; cuid1341 (Box 18, Cd Jabara 1-2, Box 4, Cassette 125 B-C)
  - Jewish People's Chorus, Apr 14, 1980; cuid1342 (Box 4, Cassette 126, Box 18, Cd Jewish People's Chorus 1)
    Excerpt from performance at Yablon Center in Los Angeles, California.
  - S.J. Jokubka, Jul 28, 1983; cuid1343 (Box 18, Cd Jokubka 1, Box 4, Cassette 125 A)
    Interview covers Jokubka's background in Lithuania and activities in Argentina during the 1930s. He also speaks of his editorship of Vilnis, a Chicago-based Lithuanian-language newspaper, since 1942. Jokubka also discusses the problems of publishing ethnic newspaper and the role of cultural activities in the Lituanian-American movement.
  - Howard Johnson, Oct 17, 1979; cuid1344 (Box 1, Folder data_value_missing_cdf477656c5e54755650898b7f0ec3cb, Box 4, Cassette 127, Box 18, Cd Johnson 1)
    Interview covers Johnson's involvement in show business in Harlem during the 1930s and dancing at the Cotton Club. He also describes his politicization, his entry into the Communist party, community involvement during the 1940s, and figures such as Jackie Robinson and Paul Robeson. Johnson also analyzes the relations of blacks and whites in the Communist Party. The recording also includes a sound reel from his night class.
  - Howard "Stretch" Johnson, Jun 26, 1984 - Aug 23, 1984; cuid1345 (Box 18, Cd Johnson 2-8, Box 80, Cassette 333A-E, Box 7, Folder 50)
    Interview by Dan Cohen.
    Duration: 330 minutes in five parts; Preservation note: Poor audio quality
  - Howard Johnson, Dec 1990; cuid1346 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    This interview is a part of the series "Oral Histories of African Americans" by the Center for Oral History at the University of Hawaii at Manoa. The interview covers his activities as a performer at the Cotton Club, as a Communist Party organizer, and as an educator.
    Interview by Kathryn Takara.
  - Onni Kaartinen, Jul 7, 1984; cuid1347 (Box 18, Cd Kaartinen 1-2, Box 4, Cassette 128 A-B)
    Kaartinen discusses his Finnish-American radical background during the 1930s, the Spanish Civil War, and fraternal and political activities from the 1940s-1970s.
  - Morris (Moshe) Kaplan, April 15, 1980; cuid1348 (Box 4, Cassette 129, Box 18, Cd Kaplan 1)
    Kaplan discusses the Yiddishe Kultur Farband (YKUF) and the Jewish cultural movement in Los Angeles.
  - Maude White Katz, Oct 18, 1981; cuid1349 (Box 4, Cassette 130, Box 18, Cd Katz 1)
    Interview covers Katz's early days in the Communist Party, the fight against white chauvinism, and the Needle Trades Industrial Union's activities during the 1920s.
  - Ed Kempf, Oct 29, 1978; cuid1350 (Box 19, Cd Kempf 1-2, Box 7, Folder 52, Box 4, Cassette 131)
    Kempf discusses his role as New Jersey Regional Director of the Steel Workers Organizing Committee-Harrison-Hoboken-Jersey City, Crucible Steel, Otis Elevator, the Socialist Party, and the Socialist Workers Party during the 1930s.
  - Aaron Kertman, Apr 7, 1980; cuid1351 (Box 4, Cassette 132, Box 19, Cd Kertman 1)
    Kertman discusses the Yiddishe Kultur Farband (YKUF) and the Jewish cultural movement in Los Angeles.
  - Anton Kerzic, Jul 27, 1983; cuid1352 (Box 19, Cd Kerzic 1-2, Box 4, Cassette 133 A-B)
    Interview covers the origins of Slovenian-American fraternal movement in Waukegan and North Chicago, Illinois. Kerzic also covers his work in a cooperative grocery store during the 1930s-1940s and work with Finnish-American fraternal group in milk coop during the 1930s-1950s. Kerzic also discusses conflict between the midwestern and eastern factions of the SNPJ (Slovenska Narodna Podporna Jednota) and his role as founder of a savings and loan bank in Waukegan.
  - Maurice Kish, Sep 23, 1979; cuid1353 (Box 10, Cassette 397 A-B, Box 19, Cd Kish 1-2)
  - Maurice Kish, Oct 29, 1979; cuid1354 (Box 19, Cd Kish 3, Box 10, Cassette 398)
  - Maurice Kish, Feb 17, 1983; cuid1355 (Box 5, Cassette 134, Box 19, Cd Kish 4)
    Brief interview with Russian-born painter about his family and his work.
  - Camp Kinderland Reunion, Jun 9, 1979; cuid1356 (Box 5, Cassette 135 A-B, Box 19, Cd Camp Kinderland 1-2)
    Recording includes reminiscences, reading of letters, and songs and dances.
  - Mary Kolehmainen, Mar 10, 1981; cuid1357 (Box 19, Cd Kolehmainen 1, Box 5, Cassette 136, Box 7, Folder 53)
    Koloehmainen discusses emigration from Finland, the activities of the Socialist Party, and the Finnish women's newspaper.
  - Mary Kolehmainen, Jul 30, 1983; cuid1358 (Box 19, Cd Kolehmainen 2, Box 5, Cassette 137)
    Kolehmainen discusses her immigration to America, life in the Finnish-American Left, the activities of Finns in Boston area during the 1930s-1940s, her role as editor of women's weekly Naisten Viiri, and the support of Finnish-American movement.
    Duration: 35 minutes
  - Joseph Korn, Apr 16, 1980; cuid1359 (Box 19, Cd Korn 1, Box 5, Cassette 138)
    Korn discusses the Yiddishe Kultur Farband (YKUF) and the Jewish cultural movement in Los Angeles.
  - Ernest Koski, Jul 31, 1983; cuid1360 (Box 19, Cd Koski 1-2, Box 5, Cassette 139 A-B)
    Koski discusses the Finnish-American Left in Mesabi Iron Range and the radical Finnish newspaper Tyomies.
  - Nettie Kravitz, Apr 1, 1983; cuid1361 (Box 5, Cassette 140 A-B, Box 19, Cd Kravitz 1-3)
    Kravitz discusses the Johnson-Forest Tendency, radical feminism, and activities on the East Coast and in Detroit, from the 1940s-1960s.
  - Rose Kryzak, Jan 4, 1982; cuid1362 (Box 7, Folder 54, Box 19, Cd Kryzak 1, Box 5, Cassette 141)
    Kryzak describes growing up in New York City, her life as a Communist Party member from 1933, her trip to Soviet Union and impressions of it, the Communist Party and women's issues, and the McCarthy period.
  - Jacob Kunin, Mar 2, 1967; cuid1363 (Box 1, Folder data_value_missing_ea2e439560b69293843fdbf4d0d0fb2b, Box 7, Folder 55)
    Kunin discusses ethnic groups and politics in Bridgeport, Connecticut during the 1920s-1940s.
  - Kay Lahusen, Jul 26, 1983; cuid1364 (Box 19, Cd Lahusen 1-3, Box 5, Cassette 143 A-B)
    Interview with Kay Lahusen (also known as Kay Tobin) covers relationship between gay liberation movement and the Left, publications, and legislative campaigns during the 1950s-1970s.
  - Ollie Leeds, Aug 9, 1983; cuid1365 (Box 19, Cd Leeds 1-3, Box 81, Cassette 370 A-C)
  - Meridel LeSueur, May 1, 1982; cuid1366 (Box 19, Cassette LeSueur 1, Box 5, Cassette 144)
    Interview details author Meridel LeSueur's recollections of Minnesota radicalism during the Great Depression.
  - Aaron Levenstein, Mar 5, 1974; cuid1367 (Box 80, Cassette 336.5, Box 19, Cd Levenstein 1)
  - Alfred Baker Lewis, Sep 8, 1967; cuid1368 (Box 1, Folder data_value_missing_a31a12feaa29d3fe642b4b15a0326bc4, Box 7, Folder 56)
    Lewis and his wife discuss the Socialist Party and the New England region during the 1910s-1940s and the civil rights movement during the 1940s-1960s.
  - Fred Lilja, Jun 28, 1983; cuid1369 (Box 5, Cassette 146, Box 19, Cd Lilja 1-2)
    Lilja discusses his immigration to the United States and his work as itinerant miner, lumber worker, and fisherman during the 1910s. He also covers the activities of Finnish-American Left in Monessan, Pennsylvania during the 1920s-1950.
  - Sam Liptzin, Mar 22, 1979; cuid1370 (Box 10, Cassette 399, Box 19, Cd Liptzin 1)
  - Frank Lovell, Jan 19, 1990; cuid1371 (Box 80, Cassette 312 A-B, Box 19, Cd Lovell 1-3)
  - Frank Lovell, Feb 2, 1990; cuid1372 (Box 19, Cd Lovell 4-5, Box 80, Cassette 313)
  - Luisa, May 3, 1979 and Mar 30, 1979; cuid1373 (Box 5, Cassette 148 A-B, Box 19, Cd Luisa 1-2)
    Interview documents the activities of the United Electrical Workers Local 431 at the Emerson Electric Company in Jersey City, New Jersey.
    Interview by Ruth Prago.
  - James Lustig, Oct 20, 1982; cuid1374 (Box 5, Cassette 149, Box 7, Folder 57, Box 19, Cd Lustig 1)
    Lustig discusses the activities of Hungarian-American Left in the fur-leather and electrical workers unions during the 1920s-1940s, his own role in strikes, blacklisting in the 1950s, and work on Henry Wallace's farm. Lustig also discusses his involvement with the publications Uj Elore and Hungarian-American Word during the 1950s-1980s.
  - A.B. Magil, Oct 31, 1980; cuid1375 (Box 19, Cd A. Magil 1-2, Box 5, Cassette 150 A-B)
    Interview covers Magil's in Yiddish culture in Philadelphia, life at the Daily Worker in the 1920s, and self-denial of Yiddish cultural activities for "broader field."
  - A.B. Magil, Jan 5, 1994 - Mar 27, 1995; cuid1376 (Box 7, Folder 58, Box 19, Cd A. Magil 3-9, Box 80, Cassette 332 A-F)
    Interview by Allen Thompson.
  - Vito Magli, May 15, 1983; cuid1377 (Box 5, Cassette 151 A-B, Box 19, Cd V. Magli 1-2)
    Interviews includes discussion of background as high school supporter of Vito Marcantonio in New York and youth leader of Marcantonio movement. Also covered is Magil's work as editor of Communist Italian-language paper, L'Unita and its support in mining regions and cities during the 1940s-1950s. Additionally, the interview covers Magil's retirement to Florida and reflections.
  - Mary Magner, Jan 26, 1975; cuid1378 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    Interview covers Magner's activities in the Bridgeport, Connecticut Socialist Party and role as executive secretary to Socialist Mayor Jasper McLevy from 1940-1957.
  - Robin Maisel, Feb 28 and Mar 5, 1975; cuid1379 (Box 5, Cassette 153 A-C, Box 19, Cd Maisel 1-3)
    Interview covers activities of the Socialist Workers Party during the 1960s-1970s, Maisel's work experience in print shops, and the influence of his parents' radical convictions and activities.
  - Morty Manford, Aug 6, 1983; cuid1380 (Box 20, Cd Manford 1-3, Box 5, Cassette 154 A-C)
    Interview regarding gay rights.
  - Julius Margolin, Dec 30, 1983; cuid1381 (Box 5, Cassette 155, Box 20, Cd Margolin 1)
    Interview describes Margolin's activities from 1930s-1950s. Topics include the Food Workers Industrial Union, the National Maritime Union, the World War II no-strike pledge, the Communist Party view of Trotskyism, and the Korean War.
  - Rita Margules, Jun 16, 2011; cuid1382 (Box 20, Cd Margules 1-2, Box 10)
    Interview by Mike Nash.
  - Alice Marsh, Feb 24, 1982; cuid1383 (Box 20, Cd Marsh 1, Box 5, Cassette 156)
    Subjects discussed in this interview include the activities of the Socialist Party during the 1930s and the struggle between Communists and Socialists in the Teachers Union.
  - Matteotti Club, 1977 (Box 5, Cassette 158, Box 20, Cd Matteotti 1)
    Reunion of Rhode Island activists in Sacco-Vanzetti Defense Campaign, 50 years after execution. Disscussion of defense activities, mostly by Luigi Nardella.
    - Anthony Martocchia and Philip Lamantia, Oct 31, 1982; cuid1384 (Box 7, Folder 60, Box 5, Cassette 157 A-B, Box 20, Cd Martocchia & Lamantia 1)
      Interview covers Martocchia's anarchist origins in Italy and his anti-fascist activities in Chicago during the 1920s, the San Francisco/Las Gatos anarchist group during the 1930s-1950s, and his meeting with Philip Lamantia in the 1940s.The recording also covers Lamantia's sense of support from older anarchists in the 1940s and the importance of Malatesta for Martocchia. Anarchist publications in the 1980s are also discussed.
  - David Mattis, Dec 28, 1979; cuid1385 (Box 20, Cd Mattis 1, Box 10, Cassette 400)
    Includes discussion of Jews in film, Yiddish culture, and the Morgen Freiheit and the Forward.
  - Grace Burnham McDonald, Aug 10, 1973 and Aug 25, 1973; cuid1386 (Box 20, Cd McDonald 1, Box 80, Cassette 360 A-B)
    Interview is part of a series of interviews intended to document the activities of the Worker's Health Bureau, which was founded in 1920.
  - Tom McGrath, Mar 9, 1977; cuid1387 (Box 20, Cd McGrath 1, Box 5, Cassette 168)
    Interview covers literature in the 1930s, poetry and the the Communist Party's Popular Front strategy, and Left Culture during the Cold War.
    Taped responses to written questions from Paul Buhle.
  - Tom McGrath, undated; cuid1388 (Box 20, Cd McGrath 2, Box 80, Cassette 345)
    Recording of McGrath's reminiscences of the Chelsea neighborhood of New York during the 1930s-1940s, including the character of the neighborhood and radicalism there. Personalities discussed include Ray Condon, Mac and Maggie McLain, and Harold Gates. Topics include relationships with various unions in Chelsea neighborhood, waterfront workers and unions (including the National Maritime Union), a local radical newspaper called the Shamrock, McGrath's job with International Labor Defense, and conflicts with the Christian Front and German American Bund. He also speaks about his activities in Los Angeles in the 1950s. The second of the recording part contains additional information McGrath's background, including his introduction to radical left politics and student activism at University of North Dakota and Louisiana State University.
  - Ernest Rice McKinney, Feb 25, 1983; cuid1389 (Box 5, Cassette 169, Box 20, Cd McKinney 1, Box 8, Folder 1)
    Biographical interview with important African American radical, born in 1886. Topics covered include his youth and education, activities as Socialist during the 1910s, involvement with the Communist Party during the 1920s, his period as a "Musteite" during the 1930s and a "Shachtmanite" during the 1940s, the Unemployed Leagues, and A. Philip Randolph.
  - Vida McLevy, Nov 4, 1966; cuid1390 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Topics discussed include the Socialist Party in Bridgeport and the career of her husband Jasper McLevy as Socialist Mayor of Bridgeport, Connecticut from 1933-1957.
  - Medem Jewish Socialist Group/Forum on Jews and the Left, Feb 26, 1982; cuid1391 (Box 20, Cd Medem 1-2, Box 5, Cassette 159 A-B)
    Discussion by Paul Buhle and Arthur Liebman on Jews and the Left in the United States from 1890-1982, with questions from audience and response.
  - Clarina Michelson, Oct 29, 1979; cuid1392 (Box 5, Cassette 164, Box 8, Folder 3, Box 20, Cd Michelson 1-2)
    Interview documents strikes of department store workers.
  - Nick Migas, Mar 15, 1983; cuid1393 (Box 20, Cd Migas 1, Box 5, Cassette 160)
    Interview covers unionism and politics in Gary, Indiana during the 1930s-1940s, the relationship between ethnicity and race and nationalism, and the Wisconsin National Farmers Union in the 1950s.
  - John Mitchell, Mar 30, 1981; cuid1394 (Box 5, Cassette 161 A-B, Box 20, Cd Mitchell 1-2, Cassette 161A-B)
    Interview covers the activities of the Packinghouse Workers and Communist Party in Boston, Massachusetts during the 1940s-1950s.
  - Eva Mizara, Jun 24, 1983; cuid1395 (Box 20, Cd Mizara 1, Box 5, Cassette 162)
    Access Restrictions
    Interview closed, except with permission of Eva Mizara.
    Interview documents Lithuanian-American radicalism during the 1920s-1960s.
  - Mother Audley Moore, 1972; cuid1396 (Box 5, Cassette 163 A-B, Box 20, Cd Moore 1-2)
    Interview documents Moore's youth in New Orleans, the Marcus Garvey movement during the 1920s, the Communist Party in Harlem during the 1930s, and her break with the Communist Party.
  - Mother Audley Moore, Dec 23, 1981; cuid1397 (Box 20, Cd Moore 3, Box 5, Cassette 163, Box 8, Folder 5)
    Interview documents Moore's experiences in the Communist Party in Harlem during the 1930s.
  - Anna Morgan, Jan 22, 1981 - Jan 29, 1981; cuid1398 (Box 20, Cd Morgan 1-4, Box 5, Cassette 165 A-D)
    Morgan discusses her Boston childhood, life in Cuba in 1917, and Chicago in the Depression. She also covers the activities of the Communist Party in Champaign, Illinois, Indianapolis, Indiana, and Columbus, Ohio during the 1930s-1950s.
  - Gussie Moskowitz, Jun 4, 1976; cuid1399 (Box 5, Cassette 166, Box 8, Folder 6, Box 20, Cd Moskowitz 1)
    Moskowitz discusses her Hungarian-American background, the activities of the furriers union, the Communist Party, and general reflections.
    Interview by Daniel Czitrom.
  - Elma Munckton, Nov 9, 1983; cuid1400 (Box 20, Cd Munckton 1, Box 5, Cassette 167, Box 8, Folder 7)
    Munckton discusses her experiences on a farm in Finland during the 1890s, emigration to the United States, life for domestic workers, and the activities of the Finnish-American Left in Bay Area during the 1920s-1960s.
  - Emmanuel Muravchik, Dec 6, 1973; cuid1401 (Box 20, Cd Muravchik 1-3, Box 80, Cassette 337)
  - Jim Murray, Jun 20, 1984; cuid1402 (Box 80, Cassette 335, Box 20, Cd Murray 1-2, Cassette 346)
    Discussion regarding Cultural Correspondence.
  - Rosemarie Muscat, Apr 13, 1980; cuid1403 (Box 20, Cd Muscat 1, Box 5, Cassette 170, Cassette 170A-B)
  - Lillian N., May 19, 1982; cuid1404 (Box 20, Cd Lillian 1, Box 8, Folder 8, Box 5, Cassette 147)
    Interview covers activities at Brooklyn College, in the National Students' League, and with the Medical Bureau of Aid to Spanish Democracy during the 1930s.
  - Morris Nadelman, Apr 8, 1980; cuid1405 (Box 20, Cd Nadelman 1-2, Box 5, Cassette 171 A-B, Box 8, Folder 9)
    Nadelman discusses his Yiddish Anarchist origins in Russia, Yiddish Anarchist activities in Los Angeles from the 1920s-1980s, Rudolf Rocker's personality and his circle, the activities of the Arbeter Ring (Workmens' Circle), and fund-raising for victims of Spanish Civil war.
  - Luigi Nardella, Mar 1978 and Sep 29, 1982; cuid1406 (Box 5, Cassette 172 A-C, Box 20, Cd Nardella 1-3, Box 8, Folder 10)
    The first two disks or tapes are comprised of an oral history interview taken by Paul Buhle on September 29, 1982.
    The third tape or disk is a speech delivered to Rhode Island Labor History Forum at Knight Public Library in Providence regarding unemployed movement in Rhode Island during the 1930s.
    Duration: 116 minutes in three parts; Preservation note: on third part volume is very low
  - Al Nash, Dec 8, 1983; cuid1407 (Box 80, Cassette 336, Box 21, Cd Nash 1)
  - Steve Nelson, 1981; cuid1408 (Box 6, Cassette 173 B, Box 8, Folder 11, Box 21, Cd Nelson 1-4, Box 5, Cassette 173 A)
    Interview covers unemployed activities in Chicago, activities in anthracite coal districts, and the Popular Front and the Spanish Civil War.
    Interview by Rick Wormser.
  - Walter Nelson, Apr 17, 1999; cuid1409 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    Interview covers Nelson's family history, education and work, and his involvement in the World Socialist Party (formerly Workers Socialist Party and Socialist Educational Society).
    Interview by Katherine Brucher.
  - Esta Nette, 1978; cuid1410 (Box 10, Box 21, Cd Nette 1)